# ÁNGELA PATRICIA PÉREZ LORA

Transversal 88B No. 23D-81  $\diamond$  Bogotá D.C, Colombia 110911 (+571) 8148589  $\diamond$  (+57) 3132865381  $\diamond$  patriciapl2192@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

Chemical engineer with complementary studies in analytical physicochemical analysis and professional experience in research and project development. Enthusiastic for the clean technology implementation and development of projects that have a social impact. I am appasionate for team work and innovative solutions to environmental issues. I have habilities of leadership, effective communication, planning and goals achievement. I consider that I have creative and analytic thought focused on results.

### ACADEMIC ACHIVEMENTS

Thesis: Mechanic and physic proporties study of thermoplastic elatomers (TPEs) for alternate product development to vinyl fabrics. Bogotá, 2014. Directed by the professor Felipe Salcedo, PhD of Los Andes university and the Company Proquinal S.A.

Project of conceptual design for a butadiene plant: Development of a butadiene production plant. Los Andes university. Bogotá, 2013.

Product development research: Dilatant fluid implementation for the elaboration of bike helmets

Prize Academic excelence granted to the student with the highest academic average. Gimnasio Granadino school. Bogotá, 2009.

### **EDUCATION**

## University of los Andes, Bogotá D.C, Colombia

2014

BSc in Chemical Engineer

# High School Degree, Bogotá D.C, Colombia

2009

Gimnasio Granadino School

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Panzenu Foundation

April 2016 - July 2016

Chemical Analyst

Bogotá D.C - Colombia

- · A project execution in Toxicology area of the Bogota public health laboratory. Research, detection and analysis of heavy metals in biological samples of a Colombian population in vulnerable state.
- · I did the standardization of the analytic method by using: Atomic absorption spectrophotometry with graphite furnace, with the guarantee of results repetitivity and reproducibility.
- · I executed the quality control process and I did the correct information management.
- · I managed the data and stadictical analysis of the results.
- · I supported toxicology analysis to environmental samples: air filters and water.

### Polinsumos Colombia S.A.S

Sales Engineer

February 2015 - January 2016 Boqotá D.C - Colombia

· Representation of Sasol Wax company in the industrial lines: personal care, pharmaceutics, inks, scholar products and candles. I had to carry out technical assistance and support all the costumers developments.

- · I carried out product developments with the research and development department. I obtained that some of the Company products were technically accepted by different industries.
- · I made a market study. I did product homologations and sales closing. I achieved local sales opening in Colombia, closing purchases in each line.
- · I positioned the Sasol Wax brand in all the industrial lines by my charge, achieving the recognition of Polinsumos as the exclusive representant of Sasol Wax in Colombia.
- · I lead the launching of the product DECORNEL in Colombia of German Sasol Wax divisin for personal care products making.

### **COURSES - CONFERENCES**

### edX, Microsoft, United States

September 2016

Introduction to data analysis using Excel. Course that gives basic knowledges for data analysis by using dinamic tables of Excel.

### Secretaria de Salud, Bogotá D.C - Colombia

July 2016

Practic training in toxicological analysis of: water, biologic samples and food. Capacitations oriented for heavy metal analysis in different types of samples. Lead in environmental samples, mercury in biological samples and food, nickel in biological samples, among others.

### Innovacin y tecnologa LTDA, Colombia

February 2016

Teoric and practice course of Atomic Absorption Spectrophotometry in the Graphite Furnace Technique. Course about the technique Atomic Absorption Spectrophotometry as a tool for chemical element detecting, in particular, heavy metals detection.

### Consejo profesional de Ingeniera Qumica, Colombia

October 2015

Cosmetic chemical as a entreprenaurship and inovation tool. Course of the skin structure and the action that different active compounds has over the skin. Formulations analysis of different cosmetic products.

### Servicio Nacional de aprendizaje SENA, Colombia

July 2015

Food protection and consevation. Protocols management that guarantee the quality in the food industry, like good manufacture practices.

### edX, Delf University of technology, Netherlands

December 2015

Technology for biobased products. Design and technology implementation that uses waste of food industry as a raw material for chemical product elaboration.

### Los Andes University, Bogotá D.C - Colombia

November 2013

Physical chemistry of polimeric systems. Course of chemical engenering master that covered all the physico chemistry properties of polymers needed for characterization making.

### Los Andes University, Bogotá D.C - Colombia

November 2013

PVC and sustainability. Participation of Colombian industries and the academy in a discusin about different alternates to vynil polyclorure that have a lesser environmental footprint.

### **LANGUAGES**

**English** Read, speak, and write with B2 level - TOEFL Score: 94

Spanish Native

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Matlab<sup>®</sup>, Aspen Plus- Aspen Properties- Aspen Hysys, Minitab<sup>®</sup>, Pro II, Microsoft Office Excel

### PERSONAL INITIATIVES

### Volunteering

- · Volunteer teacher of maths and socioemotional abilities to kids of 10 and 11 years old with low resorces. Con las Manos Foundation 2017.
- · Volunteer social work in life project orientation in students in the last year of high school. Alianza educativa association 2011.

### Others

- · Entreprenaurship project in plants sales with personalized pots and terrariums by using fiendly materials. Tienda Maticas 2017.
- · Urban Agriculture capacitation to take advantage of small spaces in some houses and the city. Jardín Botánico José Celestino Mutis 2015.
- · Logistic support to cultural and academic events in the university. Los Andes University 2010-2014.